Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and we have a delicious Italian food lesson for you today.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一堂美味的意大利美食课。
That's right.
没错。
We are at an Italian restaurant and we are ordering food.
我们在一家意大利餐厅，正在点餐。
So this is going to be very helpful next time you are at an Italian restaurant with your
所以下次你和朋友去意大利餐厅点菜时，这会非常有用。
friends and you're ordering up some dishes.
点一些菜肴。
Let's take a listen to our dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk about what's going
我们先听一下对话，稍后再回来讨论。
on.
发生了什么。
Good evening ladies.
晚上好，女士们。
My name is Josh and I'll be your server tonight.
我叫Josh，今晚是你们的服务员。
May I take your order?
可以点餐了吗？
Do you have any recommendations?
你有什么推荐吗？
Well, I personally like the chicken penne with cream mushroom sauce.
嗯，我个人喜欢奶油蘑菇酱鸡肉通心粉。
But the prawn fettuccine is also very nice.
但大虾宽面也很不错。
I'd like to have the grilled chicken.
我想要烤鸡肉。
But can I have spaghetti instead of penne?
但能把通心粉换成意大利面吗？
Of course, ma'am.
当然可以，女士。
And for you?
您呢？
I'll have the horse tripe.
我要马肚。
All right, we're back and now let's take a look at all those delicious Italian dishes
好了，我们回来了，现在来看看那些美味的意大利菜肴。
on Language Takeaway.
在“语言要点”环节。
So first of all, we have two different kinds of sauce really.
首先，我们实际上有两种不同的酱汁。
The first is cream mushroom.
第一种是奶油蘑菇。
So what's a cream sauce, Marco?
那么，Marco，什么是奶油酱？
A cream mushroom sauce.
奶油蘑菇酱。
So basically, this is cream from milk and you have mushrooms in it.
基本上，这是用牛奶做的奶油，里面加了蘑菇。
And I don't know, I think everyone has seen it.
我不知道，我想大家都见过。
It's a very thick white sauce.
这是一种很浓稠的白色酱汁。
It has little slices of mushrooms in it.
里面有小片蘑菇。
It's kind of sweet.
有点甜。
That's right.
没错。
And so oftentimes you see there's a lot of cream in it.
所以经常能看到里面有很多奶油。
And so oftentimes you see there's cream sauces, which are white, and tomato sauces, which
所以经常能看到奶油酱是白色的，番茄酱是红色的。
are red.
红色的。
And this here is a cream sauce, so it's white and it's got chunks of mushroom in it.
这里的是奶油酱，所以是白色的，里面有大块蘑菇。
Very tasty.
非常好吃。
And the waiter also offered prawn with the pasta.
服务员还推荐了大虾配意面。
So what is a prawn?
那么什么是大虾？
Prawn fettuccine.
大虾宽面。
So prawn is like a big, it's like a word for shrimp.
大虾就像是一种大的，是虾的另一种说法。
I always think of jumbo prawns, which are these big, big, big shrimps.
我总想到巨型大虾，就是那种很大很大的虾。
So they're basically the same thing.
所以它们基本上是一样的。
Shrimp and prawn are basically the same.
虾和大虾基本上是一样的。
That's right.
没错。
And they're a seafood that when they get cooked, they curl.
它们是一种海鲜，煮熟后会卷曲。
So they look like a circle, but they're pinkish or red.
所以看起来像圆圈，但颜色偏粉或红。
That's right.
没错。
They're very tasty.
它们非常好吃。
Okay, so now let's take a look at the different types of pasta.
好了，现在我们来看看不同类型的意面。
So we have three different types of pasta that the waiter suggested.
服务员推荐了三种不同类型的意面。
So the first one is...
第一种是...
Okay, we're going to say all three in the American way, but I'm going to tell you the
好的，我们打算用美式发音说这三种，但我会告诉你。
Italian way is quite different.
意大利语发音很不一样。
So I'll say that afterwards.
所以我之后再说。
The first is penne.
第一种是通心粉。
Okay.
好的。
So this is a type of pasta.
这是一种意面。
What does it look like?
它长什么样？
It is like a small tube.
像一个小管子。
So maybe three centimeters long, and it is round and it has a hole in the middle.
大概三厘米长，是圆的，中间有个洞。
And so it's a kind of pasta.
所以这是一种意面。
And what about the fettuccine?
那宽面呢？
So fettuccine is a long noodle, but it's flat.
宽面是一种长面条，但它是扁平的。
It's not round, it's flat.
不是圆的，是扁的。
Fettuccine.
宽面。
So it kind of looks like a shoelace.
所以它看起来有点像鞋带。
Yeah, it's long and flat.
是的，又长又扁。
And then we have spaghetti, which I think many people know, and this is probably the
然后我们有意大利面，我想很多人都知道，这可能是。
most popular one.
最受欢迎的一种。
That's right.
没错。
Spaghetti is very long, just like fettuccine, but it's very, very thin and round.
意大利面很长，就像宽面一样，但非常细而且是圆的。
So it kind of looks like maybe a pencil, a very long pencil.
所以它看起来有点像铅笔，一根很长的铅笔。
But very thin, more like hair, actually.
但非常细，实际上更像头发。
And there are thin kinds, so they have a special name.
还有细的种类，它们有专门的名字。
But this is just a normal pasta that you will see everywhere.
但这只是你随处可见的普通意面。
It's very long and you can twirl it.
它很长，你可以卷起来。
You can spin it around your fork.
你可以用叉子绕它。
Okay, so that's what we have.
好了，这就是我们有的。
We have penne, fettuccine, and spaghetti.
我们有通心粉、宽面和意大利面。
Now, the other woman ended up ordering horse tripe.
结果，另一个女人最后点了马肚。
Now this is also another Italian dish.
这也是另一道意大利菜。
What is this exactly?
这到底是什么？
Well, horse is the animal, so this is tripe that comes from a horse.
嗯，马是动物，所以这是来自马的肚。
But tripe is a certain part of the animal that we, it's a food name actually.
但肚是动物的一部分，实际上是个食物名称。
So when we eat the stomach lining, the part of the stomach that goes around the stomach,
所以当我们吃胃壁，也就是胃周围的那部分，
it's kind of squishy, soft.
它有点软软的、嫩嫩的。
That is called tripe.
那就叫肚。
And you can have tripe from many different animals, like cows or pigs.
你可以从很多不同动物身上得到肚，比如牛或猪。
But in this case, it's horse tripe.
但在这个例子里，是马肚。
So it's basically that thick piece of like spongy material around the animal's stomach.
所以它基本上就是动物胃周围那层厚厚的、像海绵一样的物质。
When you cook it, it looks very funny.
当你煮它的时候，看起来很有趣。
So this is actually a famous Italian dish as well, right?
所以这其实也是一道著名的意大利菜，对吧？
I think so.
我觉得是的。
I think they eat it in the South more, but you can definitely get tripe in a lot of different
我想南方人吃得多一些，但你肯定能在意大利很多不同地方找到肚。
places in Italy.
地方。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
So there you have it.
就是这样。
A lot of different dishes, Italian dishes.
很多不同的菜，意大利菜。
We've taken a look at a couple of pasta dishes.
我们看了几道意面菜。
Why don't we take a break, listen to the dialogue again, and we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
我们休息一下，再听一遍对话，然后回来继续流利度训练。
Good evening, ladies.
晚上好，女士们。
My name is Josh and I'll be your server tonight.
我叫乔什，今晚是你们的服务员。
May I take your order?
可以点菜了吗？
Do you have any recommendations?
你有什么推荐吗？
Well, I personally like the chicken penne with cream mushroom sauce, but the prawn fettuccine
嗯，我个人喜欢奶油蘑菇酱鸡肉笔管面，但大虾宽面也很不错。
is also very nice.
也很不错。
I'd like to have the grilled chicken, but can I have spaghetti instead of penne?
我想要烤鸡，但能把笔管面换成细面吗？
Of course, ma'am.
当然可以，女士。
And for you?
您呢？
I'll have the horse tripe.
我要马肚。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we're going to give you three key phrases from Fluency Builder.
现在我们要给你们三个来自流利度训练的关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
So the phrases we have selected for you today are phrases that you are sure to hear anytime
今天我们为你们选的短语，是你们去美国或任何其他英语国家餐厅时肯定会听到的。
you go to a restaurant in America or any other English speaking country.
你们去美国或任何其他英语国家餐厅时肯定会听到的。
Basically, you have a waiter who comes to you if you sit down and this is what they'll
基本上，如果你坐下来，会有服务员过来，这就是他们会说的话。
say.
说的话。
The first thing they'll say is, I'll be your server.
他们说的第一句话是，我是你的服务员。
I'll be your server tonight.
今晚我是你的服务员。
So he introduces himself.
所以他自我介绍。
He says, good evening, ladies.
他说，晚上好，女士们。
My name is Josh and I'll be your server tonight.
我叫乔什，今晚我是你们的服务员。
So when he's saying, I'll be your server, it's another way of saying, I'll be your waiter.
所以当他说“我是你的服务员”时，这是另一种说法，意思是“我是你的侍者”。
Your waiter, that's right.
你的侍者，没错。
But server can be a man or a woman.
但“server”可以是男人或女人。
And a waiter can only be a man.
而“waiter”只能指男人。
If it's a woman, it's a waitress.
如果是女人，就是“waitress”。
Okay.
好的。
So waitress for a woman, waiter for a guy.
所以女人用“waitress”，男人用“waiter”。
But if you use server, it's for men and women.
但如果你用“server”，男女通用。
Yes, I'll be your server.
是的，我是你的服务员。
And I just like to remind you that this is more common in America because in America,
我想提醒你，这在美国更常见，因为在美国，侍者或服务员需要赚小费，所以他们很友好。
waiters and waitresses or servers, they have to earn tips and so they're very nice.
侍者或服务员需要赚小费，所以他们很友好。
Aha.
啊哈。
Okay.
好的。
So this is why they introduce themselves.
所以他们自我介绍。
They are very nice to you.
他们对你很友好。
And then they ask, may I take your order?
然后他们问，可以点菜了吗？
May I take your order?
可以点菜了吗？
So the verb to take here doesn't mean to take it from you.
所以这里的动词“take”不是指从你这里拿走。
It means to ask you and then they'll write it down.
而是指问你，然后他们会记下来。
Okay.
好的。
So the server will ask you what you want to order and then we'll write it down.
所以服务员会问你想点什么，然后记下来。
And the order is what you have decided to eat.
“order”就是你决定要吃的。
So that's the food that you order.
所以那是你点的食物。
Now this next phrase is very, very handy, especially if you're in a country that maybe
现在下一个短语非常非常有用，特别是如果你在一个不太熟悉菜品的国家，或者在一家你想看看他们推荐的餐厅。
you don't know the dishes well or if you're in a restaurant that you want to see what
或者在一家你想看看他们推荐的餐厅。
they recommend.
你可以直接说，你有什么推荐吗？
You can just say, do you have any recommendations?
你有什么推荐吗？
Do you have any recommendations?
Okay.
好的。
So this is a way to ask the server what's good.
所以这是问服务员什么好吃的一种方式。
So what he thinks is good or what the restaurant serves very well.
也就是他觉得什么好吃，或者这家餐厅擅长做什么。
Okay.
好的。
So you could say, I've never been to this restaurant before.
所以你可以说，我从没来过这家餐厅。
Do you have any recommendations?
你有什么推荐吗？
Or maybe even, you know, Marco, we're having dinner and I know that you really like Italian
或者甚至，你知道，马可，我们一起吃晚饭，我知道你很喜欢意大利菜，而我对意大利菜不太了解。
food and I don't know much about Italian food.
意大利菜，而我对意大利菜不太了解。
So I can ask you, do you have any recommendations?
所以我可以问你，你有什么推荐吗？
Okay.
好的。
So this is a way of asking what is good here.
所以这是一种询问这里什么好吃的方式。
What is delicious in this restaurant?
这家餐厅什么好吃？
What's good to eat.
有什么好吃的。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
行。
So three phrases there for you.
所以这里给你三个短语。
Why don't we take another short break and let's listen to the dialogue for the last
我们为什么不短暂休息一下，然后听最后一遍对话？
time.
最后一遍。
Good evening, ladies.
晚上好，女士们。
My name is Josh and I'll be your server tonight.
我叫乔什，今晚是你们的服务员。
May I take your order?
可以点餐了吗？
Do you have any recommendations?
你有什么推荐吗？
Well, I personally like the chicken penne with cream mushroom sauce, but the prawn fettuccine
嗯，我个人喜欢奶油蘑菇酱鸡肉笔管面，但虾仁宽面条也很不错。
is also very nice.
也很不错。
I'd like to have the grilled chicken, but can I have spaghetti instead of penne?
我想要烤鸡肉，但能把笔管面换成意大利面吗？
Of course, ma'am.
当然可以，女士。
And for you?
那您呢？
I, uh, I'll have the horse tripe.
我，呃，我要马肚。
All right.
好的。
So talking about pasta.
所以说到意大利面。
Now one thing before you mentioned that all these different types of pasta, they're basically
在你提到之前，有一点是所有这些不同类型的意大利面，它们基本上是一样的东西。
the same thing.
它们基本上是一样的东西。
They're just different shapes, right?
它们只是形状不同，对吧？
That's how you distinguish them.
这就是区分它们的方式。
Well, yeah, they're, they're basically made from the same ingredients.
嗯，是的，它们基本上是用同样的原料做的。
And so you have, most of them are kind of a yellow color, but sometimes you have pastas
所以大多数是黄色的，但有时也有深色的，比如棕色或绿色，这取决于你在面团里加了什么。
that are a dark, like a brown or a green that depends on what kind of things you put into
比如棕色或绿色，这取决于你在面团里加了什么。
the dough.
面团里。
But generally they're the same ingredients, but they are different shapes.
但通常原料相同，只是形状不同。
Like they have curly ones and they have long ones and short ones.
比如有卷曲的、长的和短的。
All right.
好的。
So how do you pronounce, uh, we said penne in, uh, in English, in American English, but
那么怎么发音呢？我们在英语里，美式英语里说 penne，但在正宗意大利语里，应该是 penne。
in proper Italian, it would be penne.
在正宗意大利语里，应该是 penne。
So you, you, you double pronounce the consonant.
所以你要双倍发音那个辅音。
What about fettuccine?
那 fettuccine 呢？
Fettuccine.
Fettuccine。
Oh, it's fettuccine.
哦，是 fettuccine。
Fettuccine.
Fettuccine。
Um, in, in American, we say, uh, fettuccine.
嗯，在美式英语里，我们说 fettuccine。
Fettuccine.
Fettuccine。
Like fettuccine Alfredo is a very common American Italian dish, but in Italian it'd
比如 fettuccine Alfredo 是一道很常见的美式意大利菜，但在意大利语里是 fettuccine。
be fettuccine.
在意大利语里是 fettuccine。
So you might hear it differently.
所以你可能会听到不同的发音。
And what about spaghetti?
那 spaghetti 呢？
Spaghetti.
Spaghetti。
Oh, you pronounce the double T as well.
哦，你也要双倍发音那个 T。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So, uh, you said that, uh, obviously there are a lot of other types of pasta.
所以，呃，你说了，显然还有很多其他类型的意大利面。
What about this pasta that's, uh, I think it's made of spinach.
那这种意大利面呢？我觉得是用菠菜做的。
It's green.
它是绿色的。
Yeah, that's, uh, that's just a spinach pasta.
是的，那是菠菜意大利面。
Oh, okay.
哦，好的。
So they put the spinach in the dough.
所以他们把菠菜放进面团里。
Um, but you can also find very many, um, shapes like the angel hair pasta is very popular.
嗯，但你也能找到很多形状，比如天使发丝面很受欢迎。
It's very thin.
它非常细。
That's the one I was saying is it's almost like hair.
就是我说的那种，几乎像头发一样。
It's so thin.
它太细了。
It's very, it's long as well.
它也很长。
What about those little curly tubes?
那些小卷管呢？
Um, you, they look like penne, but they're kind of curved.
嗯，它们看起来像笔管面，但有点弯曲。
They look like little, uh, ends or you have, um, macaroni, macaroni, elbow macaroni.
它们看起来像小弯头，或者有通心粉，通心粉，肘形通心粉。
We call them in America and they look like your elbow on your arm.
在美国我们这么叫，它们看起来像你胳膊上的肘部。
So we call them elbow macaroni.
所以我们叫它们肘形通心粉。
What about the ones that are, um, they have like a spiral, they kind of look like springs.
那些螺旋形的呢？它们看起来像弹簧。
Those are called fusilli.
那些叫 fusilli。
Fusilli.
Fusilli。
Uh huh.
嗯哼。
Yeah.
是的。
And you also have one that's very special.
还有一种很特别的。
This is my favorite pasta, by the way.
顺便说，这是我最喜欢的意大利面。
It's called orecchiette.
它叫 orecchiette。
Oh, what is this?
哦，这是什么？
Orecchiette.
Orecchiette。
And they look like your ear.
它们看起来像你的耳朵。
And that's what that means in Italian.
在意大利语里就是这个意思。
It means your little ear.
意思是你的小耳朵。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
Yeah.
是的。
So ear pastas.
所以是耳朵形状的意面。
Wow.
哇。
And what about ravioli?
那意大利饺呢？
This is probably one of the most, uh, famous, uh, dishes.
这可能是最著名的菜肴之一。
Ravioli.
意大利饺。
What, what is this?
这是什么？
A ravioli is like a square.
意大利饺像是一个方形。
It's like a square pasta.
它像是一种方形的意面。
But it's more like a pocket or a pillow.
但更像是一个口袋或枕头。
And inside you have ingredients like meat or cheese usually is very popular.
里面通常有肉或奶酪等馅料，非常受欢迎。
Right.
对。
So you have this cheese inside this little, this little packet.
所以这个小包里装着奶酪。
This little, yeah.
这个小包，是的。
This little dough.
这个小面团。
It's very soft and very warm.
非常柔软，非常温热。
And then on top sometimes people like to put butter or tomato sauce.
然后上面有时人们喜欢放黄油或番茄酱。
Okay.
好的。
It's really delicious.
真的很好吃。
So that's the main difference, like, this was obviously, all the pastas that we mentioned,
所以主要区别是，显然，我们之前提到的所有意面，
they're just, uh, they don't have anything inside them.
它们里面都没有任何东西。
No, they're just dough.
不，它们只是面团。
And a ravioli is a special kind of pasta that's like a, it's almost like a dumpling in a way.
而意大利饺是一种特殊的意面，有点像饺子。
It's, it's stuffed.
它是带馅的。
It has something inside.
里面有什么东西。
It has things inside.
里面有东西。
All right.
好的。
Really interesting.
真有趣。
I think Italian cuisine is among one of the most famous foods in the world.
我认为意大利菜是世界上最著名的美食之一。
And, uh, well you should let us know if, what is your favorite Italian dish?
那么，你应该告诉我们，你最喜欢的意大利菜是什么？
Please let us know.
请告诉我们。
Our website is EnglishPod.com and when you're there you could find out what our favorite
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com，在那里你可以找到我们最喜欢的
dishes are.
菜肴。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys there.
我们那里见。
Bye.
再见。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。